foreign
[Music]
menopause not only have the lowest rates
of hot flashes in the US they also have
the lowest rates of vaginal dryness
might it be due in part further greater
soy consumption one consensus panel of
experts conclude that soy can be
considered a first-line treatment for
menopausal hot flashes and night sweat
symptoms but what about for vaginal
dryness there have been a few studies on
the topical application of soy
isoflavone vaginal gels which in general
have shown beneficial effects for
example showing a significant
Improvement in dryness and pain with
intercourse over Placebo gels in fact
roughly on par with estrogen cream and
head-to-head test but what about just
eating soy
isoflavones improve female sexual
dysfunction of mice significantly
increasing vaginal blood flow but what
about in people
the data using isolated soy supplements
is mixed some studies totally flop
showing no benefit over Placebo all the
way up to study showing comparable
efficacy when pitted head-to-head
against hormone therapy for both hot
flashes and muscle pain as well as
vaginal dryness with no significant
differences between the two and of
course soy has the benefit of no
increased risk of breast and uterine
cancer or cardiovascular disease unlike
systemic hormonal menopause therapy what
about soy Foods though rather than soy
supplements well there was a muffin
study women randomized a daily muffins
containing soy flour or ground flax
seeds saw no difference in menopausal
sexual symptoms compared to wheat flour
Placebo muffins
similarly women randomized to 12 weeks
of a daily scoop of soy protein powder
experienced a significant Improvement in
sexual quality of life symptoms but not
compared to the milk protein control
group
what about soy milk and there have been
three studies
compared to women randomized to drink
about two cups of dairy milk a day for
eight months those randomized to soy
milk ended up with significantly fewer
menopausal sexual symptoms though this
appeared to be more due to symptoms
getting worse on the dairy than getting
better on the soy that reminds me of a
study in Thailand where women randomized
with soy free diet experienced worsening
of vaginal dryness and overactive
bladder type symptoms but adding extra
soy didn't seem to make them better
the second soy milk study found about
two cups a day over two months appear to
drop vaginal and sexual symptoms by a
whopping 60 to 70 percent compared to
the do-nothing control group but since
the control group didn't drink anything
special it's impossible to rule out
Placebo effects
the latest study found significant
improvements in sexual symptoms after
just six weeks of less than a cup of soy
milk a day but again the control group
did nothing so the soy milk work we
really don't know but it can't hurt to
give it a try
unless you overdo it
a 44 year old New Yorker presented to
her gynecologist with an increase in
desire that required her to
self-stimulate to orgasm approximately
15 times daily turns out a month before
she started eating in excess of four
pounds of soy Foods a day thankfully
within three months of cutting back her
desire cooled to the point that she was
able to engage in satisfying sexual
activity only twice daily
thank you